

- +1 (504) 333-9446
- nguyen.rickyh@gmail.com
- Chicago, Illinois, USA
- ☑ rnguyen6.github.io

SUMMARY

Computer engineer with experience in field installation, product lifecycle management (PLM), and improving quality of customer data networks and its interconnected systems. Demonstrated ability to provide local and distance (remote and travel) support on troubleshooting hardware and software for workstations, server and domains, and electrical amplifiers. Strong knowledge of network cable plant design processes including fiber optic and copper installation, security through access control lists and internet protocols, and vulnerability control through information assurance (IA) hardening.

EXPERIENCE

Engineering Applications Analyst | Shure Incorporated

Chicago, IL

- Nov 2021 Present
- IT expert supporting engineering divisions for software applications and PLM integration and deployment
- Completed 3 PLM projects improving on customer ease of use, user interface, and program stability
- Successfully met 94% SLA response time and 82% resolution time for incident and request tickets
- Managed over 150 applications across major operating systems for installs and deployments to servers and clients

Systems Engineer II | Raytheon

San Diego, CA Aug 2019 - Nov 2021

- Field engineer supporting radar systems, wide area networks, machinery & ship control, and voice & video systems
- Responsible engineering agent and/or subject matter expert for 5 hull, mechanical, and electrical (HM&E) systems
- Provided customer assistance in IA hardening and troubleshooting for shipboard electronics of 10 ships
- Developed, tested, and maintained the upgraded intranet for the HM&E systems of 4 ships
- Alteration and installation team (AIT) lead of major network modifications for 2 ships spanning year long installs
- Completed over 400 computer deliverables, from lab construction and load to field test and maintenance

CS Teacher Assistant | Illinois Institute of Technology

Jan 2016 - Feb 2019 Chicago, IL

- Assisted approximately 30 students per semester in introductory computer science object-oriented programming
- Led weekly lab sessions, answering questions and concerns in the Java and Python languages
- Reselected as a preferred applicant 6 consecutive semesters until graduation

Image and Electronic Systems Expert | IIT UAV Experimentalists

Chicago, IL Aug 2016 - June 2017

- Collaborated in constructing an unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) emphasizing production speed and modularity
- Designed the imaging systems for autonomous object avoidance and assisted in cyber security protocols
- Participated in the 2017 AUVSI SUAS competition at Naval Air Station in Patuxent River, MD

Electronics Repair Technician | Freelance

New Orleans, LA Aug 2011 - May 2014

- Provided services to troubleshoot consumer hardware, modify software, and add artistic modifications
- Specialized in repairing mobile cell phones, video game consoles, and other small consumer electronics

EDUCATION

MS in Computer Engineering [GPA: 3.65] | Illinois Institute of Technology

Chicago, IL

May 2019

Concentration: Computer Hardware Design

Coursework: VLSI Systems Design, Computer Architecture, Hardware Software Codesign, Operating System Design, Computer Network Security, Wireless Networking, Digital Systems-on-Chip Design

BS in Computer Engineering [GPA: 3.70] | Illinois Institute of Technology

Chicago, IL

May 2018

Coursework: Circuit Analysis, Digital Systems, Microcomputers, Signals Systems, VLSI Design, Object Oriented Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Systems Programming, Operating Systems, Database Organization

SKILLS

Engineering Applications CAD (Inventor, NX, Rhino3D) Analog Sim (Virtuoso, HSpice) Mathematica & MatLAB

IT Applications PLM (SAP, SCCM) SSH (PuTTy, OmniVista) **Directory Services**

Programming Languages OOP (Python, Java, C++) HDL (VHDL, Verilog) Markup (LaTeX, HTML)

Other Microsoft Office Photoshop & Premiere 3D Printing